good morning it's yours truly professor
Johanna Sophia of Johanna's raw foods
and coaching and you're super happy body
coach and we're gonna make us a super
happy body but this week's topic is who
owns my body and I just want to really
look at that question in a as much
straightforward of a view as possible
because we delude ourselves with this
body ownership
you know like crazy and okay if we say
if we're religious and of course the
answer is very simple God owns this body
and everything that's happening to it is
determined by God but then still humans
have to execute the respective action to
be taken out on this body and interfere
with it or rescue it or whatever the
case may be who owns this body still
remains the question and if you are a
woman and you happen to have had a
sexual relationship and you happen to be
pregnant maybe intentionally maybe
unintentionally suddenly you don't own
this body anymore in some people's view
and then reproduction if it is a choice
becomes a condemnation or no interaction
no sexual interaction with the other
X is per minute or is possible because
accidents happen etc so it's it's really
an interesting question because we're
still struggling with this one we still
haven't really understood that this body
here is my body I incarnated into this
body I have the responsibility for it
and if I permit
a next being to grow inside of this body
I still own the rest of my body I still
own my body including that new body that
is forming until it is external and able
to breathe and live on its own of course
no human baby that's the other that's
the other conundrum you know no human
baby can be just put out in the woods
and live on its own yes it has happened
that a wolf mother took care of a human
baby and the baby grew up to be a wolf
but that's not what I'm talking about no
human can be put out into the world and
live and of course most mammals most
mammal babies can't live on their own
immediately they need feeding they need
yeah mostly feeding grooming if they're
supposed to survive in the wild and
teaching and imitation of their mothers
and others around them so so
reproduction is the conundrum we are
still dealing with in terms of who owns
my body does the state own my body does
there and when we go historically then
of course we get to nobody owned their
own body
period I guess King
and queens to a certain extent but they
too could just be beheaded if it's so
pleased somebody who claimed the throne
or the victor in a war situation the
victor then had claim to any and all of
the royalty submitted or in that victory
conquered in that victory
so the ownership of our body as being
our own is a new concept in this era of
known history prior to that we don't
really know how communities have dealt
with body and body ownership but we know
and there's plenty of examples in the
Bible in the Quran in other old
scriptures that parents owned the bodies
of their children until they were adult
and there's different rules and
different times and different religions
as to when that body officially belongs
to the new person so if I have a child
and lived 500 years ago and I decide to
chop its hand off I have that right I
mean it is gross it is absolutely crazy
if I have a daughter and I'm a man or
have a nice thousand years ago of five
thousand I don't know how far goes back
in some older Old Testaments you can
find the text then I have the right to
the virginity of that daughter or niece
or whatever the arrangement may be with
the parents of that meets if I have a
child and I want to sell that child into
marriage for financial or other
advantages business collaboration
advantages I was able to sell that child
into bondage or into marriage or into
whichever because whichever the case may
have been because that child was
consider
my property when we have human bodies as
property and this whole patriarchal era
has all been about ownership as opposed
to being well both being what you're
predestined to be according to your
caste you're according to your
professional status of your parents your
grandparents etc according to your
bloodline is what I'm looking for here I
suppose you were predestined to be what
that bloodline decreed you to be and you
were predestined to only come into
ownership of your body if you were a
male and well to a very limited extent
because the royalties rulers could still
decree anytime to use your body as
cannon fodder or chopped liver for that
matter and send you out into war whether
it was with a machete or whether it was
with a gun it's the same thing and it
still is the moment you can be decreed
to become drafted to become a piece of
flesh to fight for the the nation that
you happen to belong to um you don't own
your body you do not own your body and
all this talk about you know take care
of your body and it's your body and you
know that falls completely flat when we
take that into consideration and this is
a new thing that we can actually decide
what we want our body to look like that
we can actually decide what we put into
our body in terms of food and/or
medicine and or poison and or healing
stuff so this is a new thing and it's so
important because we forget that concept
defying
our selves today we're kind of we're the
property of the medical system literally
with the guinea pigs we're that you know
that what the doctor says goes and if
you don't abide by the rules you're
gonna be excluded from the medical
community from your insurance from your
etc so you don't decide what happens to
your body if somebody says oh you got to
do this operation you gotta do chemo you
gotta do take these poison pills and we
take those poison pills because our
bodies are owned by that industry and
everything is done to make sure that we
abide by the rules even though they're
not they're not even law they can't be
law because that would literally cement
the fact that your body is not your own
that you are owned and of course that's
what's being done with with mass
vaccinations with mass anything that
your body suddenly your children's body
and your adult body is no longer your
own but is owned by those hierarchical
forces those same structures that
allowed the king to send you to war and
allows your respective government to
decree that you need to go and do X so
let us not delude ourselves the more we
can hold on to the ownership of our body
the more we can do good and heal and
strengthen and empower our body the more
we can actually be ourselves be
individuals be in charge of our own life
and that's a scary thing because nobody
tells you what to do when you're in
charge of your own body you don't just
have to follow orders you have to come
up with your own orders with your own
discipline so and again I talked much
more than I thought I would but
this is how important this topic is who
owns your body is huge and that's why
we're gonna work it out now this body of
ours and make it as strong and as fit as
we can so that we can actually claim
ownership to it and do not have to turn
it into a guinea pig for the geriatric
decomposition process
aggghhhhh are governed by and fed by and
kept lingering in limbo by the powers
that be and the medications which of
course you do need when you decompose
like crazies when you don't strengthen
your body it will decompose when you
don't put the right food in your mouth
you will deteriorate and your brain will
deteriorate etc so more about that
tomorrow this whole week who owns your
body body and politics are righty-tighty
let's work it out okay and of course I
can't get up from this couch without
holding on and that is just par for the
course we need to do yeah we need to do
a hundred crouch ups today so that is
going to be the hundreds are moving on
all week and yes
66 and doing the hundreds we need to do
this because I like owning this body I
like the way it feels when I have
control over it when I wake up and I
don't have a single ache or pain or or
worry you know about the deterioration
of my body because I am the owner of
this body and I take care of it
so join me
okay this needs to go up on YouTube who
owns your body we shall do that
it's of course a holiday understand most
of you here gonna be sleeping in and not
work up but I went to stretch two three
four five six seven eight and swing and
two and three and four I love you my
planet ah I do I love you my sunshine
bring life to this universe I love you
humanity allow for intelligence and Laur
fresh thinking allow for decision making
a love for ownership of my body and it's
the only thing I do want to own by the
way I couldn't care less for houses and
streets and landscapes etc but I do want
to own this body because it allows me to
be healthy already
good morning whoever just joined us I'll
come and look at you in a minute
like right now we're getting going bend
your knees a little bit make sure you
show the blades up back your hip set in
so that you make your back makes a
straight line and we're going to twist
and twist two three four five six seven
eight and one two a hundred for a few
more six seven eight number three four
- wait five six seven eight
then further so we have more room and
one two three four six seven 48 49 and
50 you one two three in a minute we're
doing fists five six let's start now and
what gee sweet four five six and two two
three four five six and three to four
five six seven eight and four two three
four five six seven eight and five four
five six seven eight and six
- don't forget your eyes oops I almost
forgot seven six stitch whoo and swing
whoo so everything in hundreds means I'm
just great yeah
hey Rhonda a happy new day professor
Rhonda King
gonna call you professor now because you
better live up to your abilities you
know so much you have so much skill you
need to become the teacher now
Ronda talk to me and the way and we're
not going to do a hundred waves but
we're gonna do over there bounces and
down and bounce and bounce gonna slow
down so we can make the bounce is bigger
five six keep your hands on your hips
because it's going to be too hard one
two three to the left and five six seven
eight to the right two three four five
six seven eight and Center to six number
five two three four five six six three
four five six seven two more and 4950
and reach
and I'm gonna drink some water encourage
you to do the same
go ahead huh man ownership yeah I tell
you a little bit of something
yeah was I'm puking I had it kicks in
then another hundred way from bounces
all right back balances and kick two
four five six seven eight to the right 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 to the left 2 3 4 5 6 7 7 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 and 2 this is number 5 5 6
7 8 and 6 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
whoa yeah two days of not ha
and I still need people to join me on a
21-day challenge or even 30-day
challenge of three miles a day six days
a week because I need to get back into
running a screen walking mostly and my
foot is still acting up a little bit
have to pack it again and to ginger and
cayenne tonight more ginger than can
probably because I did it last night egg
before a lesson it was like burning all
of my god but I got to get rid of the
rest of that swelling in there from the
ligament tear I don't want any residual
you know sometimes residual swellings
can remain in your joints for years and
I just need to get rid of that like my
best girlfriend my best eat tummy for
years she couldn't walk longer distances
because there was this lump of
once-upon-a-time inflammatory liquid
something tissue you know in her ankle
and I finally took her to my
acupuncturist and lo and behold it kind
of melted away after I think just two
treatments it was gone so now she's been
walking again this this is like almost
20 years ago that we did that but yeah
it can it can be a stupid remainder
reminder of the incident and remaining
issue when it doesn't get healed up
completely so alright let's do the next
fifty and then the next fifty waves
okay two three four and five six seven
eight n heels two three four and five
six seven to the left two three
I'm going lower to make it harder for
myself so that when eight to the right
two three four and five six two three
four two three four five six seven two
more and ninety-nine one hundred
boo the challenge and siren is sitting
over there like a sphinx I'm watching
you kill yourself here she comes
right so what you say and you would just
fit naturally go to the litter boxes in
the basement oh yes yes we can okay
backbones this don't touch the chair and
as you get up you don't need it keep
your show the babies back you can do it
you can be straight oh my god when I go
anywhere now I'm like huh huh what
you're talking about and I feel like I'm
sticking my chest out like crazy but it
just looks normal to others it doesn't
look you know this looks feels normal to
me
ha feels like I'm looking here what I
got but I guess it just looks normal
like a walk straight yeah so that's what
I need to do okay
feet a little wider than hip apart toes
forward and we go down to three and box
and box 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 & 2 2 3 4 6 7 to
the left 2 3 4 5 6 7 to the right 2 3 4
5 6 and the center 2 4 5 6 7 1 4 & 1 2 3
4 5 6 7
99 100
and so to fix those inner ears if you
come across anybody who has an idea of
how to fix the little balance nodes on
the inner ear put them back into the
right place let me know I know the
doctors in New York City the only
solution that they had was something
like a really crude like knocking your
head around just to hope that maybe they
fall back into place I was like oh yeah
that's modern medicine
I know but pull your head home okay why
not electroshock right
why not lobotomy all righty we're going
to start on the Crouch ups and we're
going to go on three then I'm two and
maybe we can even go on one okay meaning
one stretch up one down one bounce and
back up because this is just taking too
long otherwise 1 2 3 down to 3 pounds 2
3 up to 3 1 2 3 down 2 3 bump 2 3 up to
3 2 this is number 3 1 and up four
down but bostic's
don't bump seven don't eight and know
about 1000 men I don't know about it
I really don't know what huh she eat
that seems an awful lot
oh okay that's a belly friendship in
between yeah I was sitting again singing
and instead of doing or talking da da da
da ya know and fifty time oh yes huh
you should probably take off my sweater
but I want to be hot
I want these muscles to grow and okay we
all needed ten crouch ups so that was
fifty belly crunches reading it 200 on
those and now I need I need my heartbeat
to calm down in between that's why I'm
taking these long pauses
cuz when it's like oh good I need to
calm down or else off my arteries okay
okay guys let's do ten on let's travel
to one cheap down - bombs - up - one two
down - bombs - up to one to two to four
down bones up five down thumbs up six
down
Oh 708 don't don't
none damn 1000 we definitely have to
slow that down well right now how are
you doing
run that so much fitter that challenge
huh what are my chocolate oh my god who
was this tiny tiny little handwriting
let's this Alaska's highest mountains
what is it not even to me this is to
Katie but once lived in this house and
has since moved to San Francisco I think
need to find her again she is so cool
hey environmentalist totally cool okay
let's do 15 more crunches and actually
we're going to do them some sitting feet
down and you can make them bigger but
hold on for me for balance and 3/4 yeah
I just don't go as far if I don't hold
on six seven hey also student to not
strain your neck so better hold on two
three four five six seven eight
a little to the left two three four to
the right and huh six seven eight and
twenty five little bit little break
really dangle your head so it's
important to really let go of your neck
muscles and your face open your mouth
and let your face hang upside down it
doesn't the older you get the more it
whether you feel it hanging in the
cheeks hanging and the last 25 I'm going
to go back up and 1 2 3 4 my stomach is
gurgling 7 hey what - I don't think you
can do it but it's loud here six seven
eight and one two three four five six
forward I'll fall off the chair like I
had almost luckily
all right the next microchips let's see
how far we can get it seems to - is the
most we can do I'm not ready for the one
I don't think even though I remember so
distinctly when I first came up with
this exercise for my warmup for my
relaxation class that I was holding in
Germany in the 1990s I needed a bunch of
times in different settings and
including in a fitness studio and there
just was stretched up on your tippy toes
stretch down bones and back up and tippy
toes and down and bounce and make up oh
let's just do that and tippy toes and I
can't go check your toes down up and
tippy toes it's actually easier it was
just what bones because it keeps you
back up and up one down and up and one
and down and bounce and up and seven and
down and up and eight and nine thirty
okay we're getting 200 push-ups
oh the backup my cops may not may not
may not go up to 100 I came out right
now that's cushion on edge and let's do
a hundred fast no big deal
right I'm sure even though we can yeah
stretching those costs is an issue right
now and one two three four five six
seven eight hey siren to put detail on
my face five six seven eight and again
two three four five six seven eight
twenty
[Music]
sorry eating her grasses so we got those
dried ones and meant to get refresh
everyone's but have not done so as you
know all tap creatures need grass as
well and they diet so I don't want her
to eat the flowers I get from the
supermarket because they'll have any
sprayed but these I process from the
yard my my yard so they're relatively
cool yeah okay and then they said I push
us or another set of crotch chips crunch
ups gotta do this turning a little bit
and up a little bit on your tippy toes
up and down and bounce and up and reach
and down and bounce and up and reach and
down
and bounce up and four and down and
bounce and five and jump and bump and
six and seven and eight
whoa yeah my pasta acting up so I don't
think I can go 200 but we can do a
hundred push-ups now where we at 25 or I
kissed you it was push-ups you tell me
Rhonda how many more push-ups do we need
to do where's everybody else
we got 23 flybys and you guys need to
come up here Laurie is here our flyby I
don't know and I can't know who you are
unless you open up the screen and then I
see your names
whoo all righty guys okay leave my
sweater on because I want these are
muscles to build my key again and one
two three four five six seven eight one
two three Oh see
said 8 and 925 really relax to really
feel like everything is fluffy
oh right siren hmm like you're all the
time you're all the time relaxed hmm not
as relaxed as fluffy though we had one
little cat went really long fluffy hair
picked her up from the barn as a kitten
and this kitten was so relaxed you could
sit her on your head she just hang there
and her and you could hang her anywhere
over your shoulder anywhere she would
just sit in her like a robot so lovely
fluffy yeah you're no fluffy but you're
pretty relaxed you're pretty cool she
wants to be near but not too and on her
own terms and I mean Anna so another 10
crouch ups okay Rhonda 25 more okay 25
more more we need to do now off the
push-up sign on then we're at 100 okay
good but we're going to do we're at 50
crouch ups I don't know whether we'll
get to it but I will do another 10 maybe
another 2
okay let's do it and to be down and
bumps and up and stretch and down and
bounce and and three and four and bumps
5.6 da-dun up seven down eight but oh
nine oh no oh oh
kitty you're giving me a break thank you
and bounce up and 10 dots and oh oh
Jesus Christ
Oh exposing myself we can get that run
up you and I
I know we can choose stick that chest up
yes we can Oh
and 25 more right and we're gonna be out
of image and one two three four five six
seven eight
any excuse any excuse to wait four five
six seven eight
last one one two three four five six
seven 99 100 oh yes we did it and this
should not be hard it's just the Crouch
ups are so hard but my body my cleavage
my employment I own it I hone it Oh clay
oh that's a good run I blame it I claim
it I hone it my ownage right back down
round I write that down from your please
oh maybe the other way around
now he goes it works either way around I
own it I blame it I own it I claim it
that nice that's nice too any which way
we got to do what we got to do to make
it the body that we want to have that's
what it's all about whatever you want to
believe god-given or no you know you
incarnated into it you're in it now you
have to take care of it now
nobody else will you got to do it of
course you can say you know once you're
in the army the army will feed you to
care you yeah but once that leg is
chopped off or the arm is chopped up or
that brain is damaged they yeah they
owned it they've done it okay but this
not just say that we can't have
accidents owning this body because we
expose ourselves to the world and
accidents happen and we can still reown
it as best we can in whatever physical
situation that is right huh
one more round of crutches wait though
let's do a couple of weights in between
sorry
this crowd Chuck business is really
throwing me for a loop
what's Rhonda saying oh come on Joanna
you can read without glasses
you gotta beit's exercises oh no I can't
name it claim it own it own it yeah all
right I can read without glasses
damn it yes I can this such a relax
those eyes
so then retina and the brain can receive
it's a weird thing and one two three
four six seven and two three four five
six seven eight and back down two three
four five six seven and eight and one
two three four five six seven eight to
the back two three four five six seven
and last one two three four five six
seven eight two more and two and fifty
all right
ten more but if I can't do them all
forgive me please huh put that blood
pressure up eat some junk this is not
junk of course this is all fruits nuts
and chocolate and actually there's some
oats in here because of the B vitamins I
would have easily accessible Peas
and I need to make a super food
chocolate superfood all right let's get
ready and we'll do these on - okay one
two down two one two one two down two
bums - up - it seems easier
two down two bums - up to four 2.25 - up
to five down thumbs up 6 down thumbs up
7 dumb bones 8 down bums none down
thumbs up Ted down don't
I'll be at 70 or 80 now ha 78 knee I'm
so proud of myself
that the air art and open up chin
forward and dangle reason with the head
dangle the shoulders
but when you're in this position it's
important to breathe into your pelvis
and you feel how your belly expands
sideways and into between your legs
thank our leg up oops
you need to think about you're looking
up my Niki thing here buzz I ain't got
my sweater on no more no more
[Music]
how about we do 25 junky kicks and then
but then I got this hundred thing that
we got to do a hundred donkey kicks just
do another ten cups and then the rest of
our weights wait you did all the weights
right we've done hey how about we got it
ambition uh I name it I claim it I own
it I own it
I love it Rhonda we make such a great
team and Ron
Tucker is here on Tucker are you doing
the Crouch apps um guys have naturally
stronger thighs so you should be able to
do those in no time okay and one - Doh -
thumbs - up to - two down and Bob's up
three down
four down five dum-dums six down but up
seven down but eight don't bounce oh no
down belt up ten dumb I'm thinking of
this Sean a song that musician wrote to
me for my show in the mud when I can't
put the words back together that's
bothering me
[Music]
ah yeah
and Simon Simon no Moomba I think was
his last name who wrote the song for me
is no longer alive either so I will
never get those words back that's too
bad in my head going around going around
and I can't you know it's it's the way
my brain works
it can remember melodies anytime but it
can't remember words it's just really
annoying I wish I could just remember
the words as sounds him and that's how I
remember memories by the way I remember
them as sounds like if somebody tells me
they're holding the phone number out
loud I have it as a sound pattern in my
head and you can write it down it's a
weird thing brains are really curious
you know and ours are wired differently
depending on whether we're more or less
you're more right brain and all the
intricate variations that you can have
it's peculiar and it's really
fascinating okay
I'm doing another ten cups and I'm going
to try and wonder that a little slower
and one and down and up and one and down
and up and sweet
and for then down and five and we had
ninety and by damage and actually my
wrist
alright challenged random and run are
you guys both done with your projects
tell me I bet you are with your habits
cuz you don't get out of breath and out
of out of tough talk here as I do okay a
couple more weeks and then the last ten
you know what we need to do we need to
go overhead in one just on four three
four elbows and one two three four and
one two three four and one two three
four and go down one two three four five
six seven eight and one two three four
five six seven now both hands together
and one huh three four five six seven
eight
hey I don't know I didn't come and
elbows up and down no goes together and
one two agent Bob sandbox two three four
hits in five six seven eight oh no that
was hard weights right are we ready for
the last ten oh we certainly are and if
it takes this half an hour we're going
to finish the hundred crouch up
yes we can yes we totally totally can
and one to duck and bunks up and one to
don't just one bones but and up and one
down but up for up five but six down but
up seven down eight
[Music]
Oh curse so bad but I'm going to put
this up on YouTube refraining from the
worst of oh lady cursing oh man and I
did this yes we did you have no idea
66 and kickin and I don't care if it's
laughable to anybody else to me it is
awesome
and we're gonna finish stretch two three
four five six seven and sweet and two
and three four I love you my planet I
love you my sunshine it's up there I
love you all of my friends and people in
all of humanity and I love you this body
that I frickin own I own it I name it I
claim it I own it I own it yes Ronna go
love you guys this is Pina stoolie
professor Johanna Sophia with a silly
one-hundredths workout 104 us old folks
is awesome it's so silly but it's so
great have a wonderful day I know this
is FINA
a holiday for some of you run how you
doing the workout I mean you work out so
much you just so much outdoor work that
I'd love to hear though what you think
and so indulge me indulge me hmm indulge
me just does that don't that little bit
little bit didn't touch me just a little
bit a little little bit okay
all right everybody have a wonderful
rest of the day I'll see you tomorrow
morning at 8 o'clock Monday through
Friday with Fitness over 50 and this
whole week is who owns your body body
and politics body and rules body and
medicine body and parenting you know so
many things body and sexuality so stay
tuned this week it's about your body
yeah love you guys and I couldn't be
prouder if you do this workout and
complete all the 100's please comment
below and claim that you did it that you
did all the 100's please we're gonna
found a club of the 100's maybe that's
what we should do you know living to 100
and claiming the 100 100 and beyond of
course is possible tell everybody I'm
gonna cut it off now bye